Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series II. Correspondence - General/Professional
  - Ritchie, R. H., Oak Ridge National Laboratory, to R.R.W., C. U., re radiation doses received at Hiroshima and Nagasaki, invitation to visit and speak [tls]; reply, 2/27/1958 [cc], 2/12/1958 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Ritchings, R. H., Research Corporation, to Dr. T. P. Wright, C. U., re patent on Wilson invention [cc, signed], 12/1/1955 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Ritson, D[avid] M., University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re plate exposures and synchrotron [tls], note [al], 8/15/1950 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Ritson, D[ave], and P[erry] Wilson, Stanford University to R.R.W., C. U., re "estimates of Perry Wilson's on possible rf superconducting system for 10 BeV synchrotron operating at 10 Kilogauss peak field" [tls], "Rf System for 10 BeV Machine" [tm]; reply, 2/27/1964 [cc], 2/6/1964 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Robbins, Robert, Army Medical Department Schools, Fort Sam Houston, Texas, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re request for reprint of paper on ""Fast Protons""[tls], note on verso [am], 1/8/1947 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur, FAS, to R. S. Rocklin, C. U., re copy of record report [cc], 5/24/1948 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur, FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re National Science Foundation Act of 1949 [pls], 3/3/1949 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur, University of Iowa, to R.R.W., C. U., re looking for job [tls]; reply, 1/11/1950 [cc], 12/15/1949 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur, FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re willingness to be nominated for council delegate-at-large in forthcoming FAS election [tls], 1/14/1954 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re Annual Rochester Conference on High Energy Nuclear Physics [tls]; reply, 11/29/1955, 10/13/1955 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur University of Rochester, to R.R.W., LNS, re 1956 Rochester Conference [tls], 12/2/1955 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re inviting Russians to 1956 conference [ml], 1/27/1956 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, Arthur University of Rochester, to R.R.W., C. U., re inviting Russians to 1956 conference [ml]; reply from Freeman J. Dyson, Princeton University, 2/23/1956 [phc]; reply from R.R.W., 2/28/1956 [cc], 2/17/1956 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Roberts, John D., C. I. T., to MPS, re resolutions regarding graduate traineeship program in MPE sciences and reimbursement of faculty salaries from research grants, votes [phc, signed], 11/17/1963 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Roberts, John D., C. I. T., to MPS, re resolution to not hand over ground-based astronomy to NASA [phc], 2/22/1965 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Roberts, John D., C. I. T., to MPS, re annual report [phc], J. D. R. to Dr. Leland J. Haworth, NSF (report) [phc]; J. D. R. to L. J. H., re NSF support of travel by American scientists to international scientific meetings [phc], 1/4/1966 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Roberts, John D., C. I. T., to MPS, re NSF Board meeting, 1/21/1966 [phc], 1/24/1966 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Roberts, Richard B., Carnegie Institution of Washington, to R.R.W., C. U., re report of the Advisory Council [tls]; reply, 1/31/1964 [cc], R. Hofstadter, Stanford University, to R. B. R., re draft for Advisory Council [phc], 1/21/1964 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Robinson, David Z., Executive Office of the President, to "Members, Panel on the Role of 'Pion Factories' in Nuclear Structure Research," re draft copy [cc, signed], "Bethe Panel" (first draft), 12/17/1963 [thc], 12/23/1963 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Robinson, David Z., Executive Office of the President, to "Members, Panel on the Role of 'Pion Factories' in Nuclear Structure Research," re use of operation of a meson factory both as injector and research tool and reconciling statement comparing meson factory and four tandem Van de Graaffs [cc], 1/9/1964 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Robinson, David Z., Executive Office of the President, to "Panel on Meson Factories," re upcoming meeting [cc, signed], 9/21/1964 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Robinson, Denis M., High Voltage Engineering Corporation, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re accelerator history [tls], 6/22/1081 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Robinson, Franklin W., C. U., to R.R.W., Ithaca, re Milton Avery artwork [tls], 9/29/1993 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Robinson, John, Agecroft, U. K., to R.R.W., Ithaca, re sculpture, art, evolution of humans [tls], note on recto [als], 1/1/1990 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Rochlin, R. S., to John Gingrich, AEC, re establishing fair procedures for personnel security clearance [cc], 6/6/1948 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Rochlin, R. S., to A. S. Wightman, Princeton University, re Princeton Association of Scientists' committee on civil liberties of scientists and information FAS assembled [cc], 6/6/1948 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Rochlin, Bob, G. E., to R.R.W., re text of article on carbon tetrachloride, work news [als], article [tm], 1/18/1952 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S., Alfred P. Sloan, Jr., and Frank A. Howard, Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, to R.R.W., C. U., re 10th anniversary celebration [tls], 9/16/1955 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Rockwood, Raymond O., Colgate University, to R.R.W., FAS, re recent conference on atomic energy and disarmament tls], 4/4/1947 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Roderick, E. H., Cavendish Laboratory, England, to R.R.W., C. U., re proton scattering experiments [tls]; reply, 12/12/1947 [cc], 12/4/1947 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Roderick, Hilliard, AEC, to R.R.W., C. U., re Sherwood program [tls], 11/21/1957 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Roe, Albert S., White Art Museum, to R.R.W., re meeting of Art Museum Board [phc], note on recto [als], 4/26/1967 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Roe, Robert A., Chairman, House committee on Science, Space and Technology from R.R.W., C. U., re support of SSC [phc]; reply, 6/6/1990 [tls], Congressional Record, 6/14/1990 [phc], 4/30/1990 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Rogers, Fred A., The Year Book Publishers, Inc., to R.R.W., C. U., re section for "Physical Handbook of Radiology" [tls], 8/21/1951 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., from R.R.W., LNS, re termination of ONR Contract Nonr 401-(12) (CU No. 7061) and transfer use of equipment to new contract Nonr 401 (51) (CU No. 7513) [cc, signed], 9/17/1963 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., to Dr. J. Howard McMillen, NSF, re 2 proposals: "Design, Development and Construction of Equipment and Instrumentation to be Used in Experiments With the Cornell 2.2 GEV Synchrotron" and "Research with the Cornell 2.2 GEV Electron Synchrotron" [phc], 11/27/1963 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., to Dr. John T. Wilson, NSF, re grant for support of research entitled "Design Study for a High Energy Electron Synchrotron" [cc], 1/29/1964 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., to Dr. John T. Wilson, NSF, re grant for support of research entitled "Second Stage of Design Study for a High Energy Electron Synchrotron" [phc], 7/7/1964 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., to Dr. John T. Wilson, NSF, re grant for support of research entitled "Elementary Particle Research with the 2.2 BEV Electron Synchrotron" [cc], 10/29/1964 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., to George S. Day, ONR, re contract [cc], 3/23/1965 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, Thomas R., C. U., to Dr. John T. Wilson, NSF, re grant for support of research entitled "Elementary Particle Research with the 2.2 BEV Electron Synchrotron," revised budget attached [cc]; Jerome H. Fregau, NSF to R.R.W., C. U., 8/12/1966, re copy of official letter awarding grant, instructions for reports [tls], J. T. W. to James A. Perkins, CU, re grant [cc], page of instructions [pi], 9/13/1966 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Rogers, W. B., C. U., to Roger Paolangeli, re "Free" Orders [cc], 9/14/1956 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Roggi, Charles J., to R.R.W., LNS, re sales in Washington [tls], note [al]; reply, 5/28/1949 [cc], 5/18/1949 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - [Rohrer], Parke, to R.R.W., re "designs at Fermi" [als], note on recto [am], 5/5/1985 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - [Rohrer], Parke, to R.R.W., re conversation about the (Gulf) war [tls], note on recto [als], [2/1991] (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - [Rohrer], Parke, to R.R.W., re reminiscences about working at Fermilab, family news, Christmas wishes [als], 12/17/1991 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Rohrer, Parke: R.R.W. reminiscence for the occasion of P. R.'s 70th birthday [pm], 6/22/1994 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Rojansky, V., FAS, to "Members of the Administrative Committee," re amendment to voting procedure [cc], 8/11/1948 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Rollefson, R., Office of International Scientific Affairs, to R.R.W., C. U., re relations with Communist China [phc], 5/1/1964 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franklin Delano), and Edgar Ansel Mowrer, National Conference on the German Problem/ Sponsoring Committee, to R.R.W., FAS, re invitation to attend conference [mls], 2/1/1947 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Rosen, Louis, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, Patricia D. Beck for Dr. Rosen, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re service under visiting Staff Member Agreement [tls], 5/28/1981 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Rosen, Louis, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re "Particle Accelerators at Age 50" [tls], 9/2/1981 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Rosen, Louis, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re invitation to visit and assist in writing preliminary proposal for addition to LAMPF [tls], 3/2/1982 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, to R.R.W., C. U., re editing Dyson article on large external beam [tls], 6/29/1956 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, to R.R.W., C. U., re seeing R.R.W. in Rochester, needs article even sooner [tls], 4/29/1957 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Ted (Edward P.), from R.R.W., re discussion in Rochester about project to construct "large and novel" international accelerator, draft [al], notes in shorthand on verso [am], [1957] (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, from R.R.W., re sending material R.R.W. promised, 11/1/1957 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re upcoming article, sending tearsheets of previously published articles [tls]; reply 11/19/1956 [cc], 11/14/1956 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, to R.R.W., C. U., re letters in response to R.R.W.'s article [tls], Walter H. Neiman, RCA Institutes, Inc., to Scientific American, re diagram in R.R.W.'s article [thc]; R.R.W. to E. P. R., 4/22/1958 [cc], 4/17/1958 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, to R.R.W., C. U., re reply of 4/22/1958, request for article "The Proton" [tls]; reply, 5/26/1958 [cc], 5/16/1958 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenbaum, Edward P., Scientific American, to R.R.W., C. U., re time schedule for article [tls]; reply, 6/13/1958 [cc], 6/9/1958 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rosenblatt, Alfred, Universidad Nacional Major de San Marcos, Lima, Peru, to R.R.W., re request for "important papers on the cyclotron" [als]; reply, 11/2/1945, 9/12/1945 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rosenblum, Mark L., University of California Hospital, San Francisco, to R.R.W., C. U., re development of "state-of-the-art" proton beam accelerator [tls], 10/15/1985 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Ross, Braxton, University of Chicago, to R.R.W., re invitation to participate in "senior seminars" [tls], 9/26/1978 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rossi, Bruno, M.I.T., to R.R.W., C. U., re Montecarlo [sic] method for showers [tls]; reply, 10/20/1950 [cc]; B. R. to R.R.W., 11/9/1950, re wish to include in book, picture showing probability distributions for 50 and 100 MeV showers [tls], 9/19/1950 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rostagni, A., University di Padova, Italy, to R.R.W., re availability of Fulbright to University of Padua, invitation to spend a year in Italy [cc]; reply, 12/18/1953 [cc], 10/6/1953 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rostagni, A., Universita' Degli Studi di Padova, Italy, to R.R.W., re Conference on "Mesons and Recently Discovered Particles" [tls]; reply, 4/4/1957 [cc], 1/24/1957 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rotblat, Joe, University of Liverpool, England, to R.R.W., re figures concerning neutron fluxes, cadmium ratios [tls]; reply, 10/15/1948 [cc], 10/7/1948 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rowe, J. E., Bell Laboratories, to R.R.W., Columbia University, re synchrotron radiation -- surface studies and photon energies up to 1500 eV [tls], 9/12/1980 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Ruark, Arthur E., AEC, from R.R.W., re invitation to forthcoming Sherwood conference on controlled thermonuclear reactions [pls]; reply, 1/31/1957 [cc]; reply, Mrs. Virginia L. Ruback for Dr. Ruark, [tls], 1/23/1957 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Ruark, Arthur E., AEC, from R.R.W., re request for Sherwood literature, submission of article "Low Pressure Hydrogen Reactor" for declassification [cc]; reply, 4/17/1957 [tls]; R.R.W. to A. E. R., 4/23/1957, re "Q" clearance [cc], AEC Personnel Security Questionnaire form; notice of declassification of article, 5/10/1957 [tls], 4/1/1957 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Ruark, Arthur E., AEC, from R.R.W., re invitation to meeting on Sherwood project [pl], information packet [pms], 9/4/1957 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Ruark, Arthur E., AEC, to "Sherwood Project Heads and Chief Investigators," re reports distribution [pls], distribution list [pm], 9/22/1959 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Ruark, Arthur E., AEC, to R.R.W., re project on plasma confinement [tls]; A. E. R. to R.R.W., 9/2/1962, re supplemental material regarding plasma confinement project [cc, signed]; reply, 9/21/1962 [cc], 8/23/1962 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Rubenstein, Meridel, Santa Fe, to R.R.W. and Jane, Ithaca, re photographs from end of August, other portraits [tls], 11/17/1989 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Rubey, William W., National Research Council, to R.R.W., C. U., re advice for Committee on Disasters to consider scientific problems involved in protection against disasters [tls], "Proposal for Disaster Study Program" [mc], tentative agenda for conference/meeting [mc, some am notes], 11/14/1951 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Rubey, William W., Washington, D. C., to R.R.W., C. U., re invitation to serve on National Research Council Final Recommendation Board for NSF Predoctoral Fellowships to nominate candidates to the Foundation (telegram) [phc], notes on verso [phc], 2/18/1952 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Rueff, P. W., Union Carbide Nuclear Company, to R.R.W., C. U., re class "Q" clearance extension [tls], 8/3/1956 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Rush, J[oseph] H., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re assisting in getting Cambridge association to pay dues, request for names of officers [tls], notes on recto [am]; reply, 10/25/1946 [cc], 10/9/1946 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Rush, J[oseph] H., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re resignation as business manager at FAS, remains Secretary-Treasurer, also national Secretary of ASAE [tls], 8/9/1947 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Rusk, Dean, Secretary of State, to R.R.W., FAS, re nongovernmental organizations interested in international affairs, upcoming conference [tls]; reply, 10/21/1963 [phc], 5/1/1963 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Rusk, Rogers D., McConnelsville, Ohio, to R.R.W., C. U., re photo of electron synchrotron for book, comments on visit [tls]; reply, 9/17/1963 [cc], 9/8/1963 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Ryan, Alvin F., AEC: Martin J. Dowd for A. F. R., to R.R.W., C. U., re travel forms for High Energy Physics Conference in Kiev in July [pls]; David P. Richtman for Morris Goldberg, AEC to "Chairman, Department of Physics," 4/6/1959, re conference on high energy physics [tls]; report on conference [cc], 6/4/1959 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Sacerdoti, Giancarlo and Reneta, to "Mr. and Mrs." R.R.W., C. U., "Many greetings" [postcard], 8/19/1964 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sachs, Mendel, University at Buffalo, to R.R.W., C. U., re address "The Sentiment of Unity in Physics" [tls], 8/22/1986 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sachs, Robert G., University of Wisconsin, from R.R.W., re editing comments [cc], 7/12/1957 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sachs, Robert G., Argonne National Laboratory, to R.R.W., C. U., re letter to Gerald Tape concerning the proposal to build a 200 GeV proton synchrotron [tls]; reply, 12/29/1965 [cc], 12/22/1965 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sachs, Robert G., Argonne National Laboratory, to "Members of the Organizing Committee HEPA," re Division of Particles and Fields [phc]; reply from E. L. Goldwasser, 6/2/1966 [pls], 5/27/1966 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sachs, Robert G., Argonne National Laboratory, to "Members of the Organizing Committee HEPA," re Division of Particles and Fields [phc], 6/10/1966 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sachs, Robert G., Argonne National Laboratory, to "Dear Colleague," re Division of Particles and Fields [phc], 7/18/1966 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Sagan, Carl, C. U., to R.R.W., Ithaca, re SDI, congratulations on winning Fermi Award [tls], 11/29/1984 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Sagan, Carl, C. U., to R.R.W., C. U., re climatic effects of nuclear war [tls], 2/10/1989 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Sagan, Carl, from R.R.W., Ithaca, re C. S. health, book "The Demon Haunted World," draft [als], 3/26/1996 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Sagan, Carl: from R.R.W., re nominating C. S. to Academy of Science, draft [al], 4/28/1992 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Sagan, Carl, Ithaca, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re C. S.'s health [tls], 5/3/1996 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Sakharov, Andrei D., Gorkiy, U.S.S.R., from R.R.W., FAS, re sympathy for tragic plight [telex], 1/30/1980 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salam, Abdus, International Atomic Energy Agency, to R.R.W., C. U., re Fermilab speech, suggested APS activities [tls], 5/29/1985 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - [Salam], Abdus, from R.R.W., re paper "Physics and the Excellence of the Life it Brings" [phc], 4/1/1986 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salant, Edward O., BNL, to R.R.W., C. U., re pre-print copies of letters in Physical Review [tls], 5/25/1950 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salent, Edward O., BNL, from R.R.W., re neutron dosage [cc]; reply, 6/2/1950 [tls], 5/25/1950 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salant, E. O., BNL, from R. W. W., re visit to Cornell and talk, interest in getting more neutron measurements at BNL to calibrate indium foil-paraffin block method of determining dosage [cc], abstract "Scintillation Counter Detection of Thermal Neutrons" [cc], 1/25/1951 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salisbury, W. W., M. I. T., to R.R.W., Princeton University, re oscillator, revised schematic diagram of Hallicrafter transmitter and small external resonator chassis [tls], 1/13/1942 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Sallaghe, R. B., Gilmour, Rothery & Co., to Mrs. R.R.W., re stolen overcoat, 10/22/1948 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salmeron, Roberto A., Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire des Hautes Energies, to R.R.W., C. U., re joint EPS/APS workshop [phc], notes on recto [als], 4/13/1988 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salmeron, Roberto A., Laboratoire de Physique Nucleaire des Hautes Energies, to R.R.W., C. U., re high energy physics meetings [tls], note on recto [als]; reply by Louis Rosen, 8/9/1989, re meeting in Greece [phc], 9/27/1988 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salmon, Vincent, M. I. T., to R.R.W., UCB, re paper "Magnetic and Electrostatic Focussing in the Cyclotron" [postcard], 3/8/1938 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Salvini, George (Giorgio), Princeton University, to R.R.W., LNS, re results on electro-magnetic cascade with Monte Carlo method [tls]; reply, 5/19/1950 [cc], 5/3/1950 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, G[iorgio], Princeton University, to R.R.W., C. U., re seeing R.R.W. at APS meeting [tls], 1/28/1952 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, G[iorgio], Istituto di Fisica Dell' Universita di Pisa, to R.R.W., C. U., re program to plan and build 600 MeV synchrotron [tls]; reply, 4/29/1953 [cc], 4/8/1953 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, INFN (Istituto Nazaionale di Fisica Nucleare) del CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Recerche), to R. R. W, C. U., re calculations and plans for new machine, would like to visit C. U. [tls], 6/19/1953 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Di Fisica, Pisa, to R.R.W., C. U., re new machine at C. U., progress on new machine at Pisa [tls], proposal for synchrotron with double vacuum chamber [mc], 2 drawings [am]; reply, 2/16/1954 [cc], 1/29/1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Di Fisica, Pisa, to R.R.W., C. U., re information on C. U. synchrotron, information on dies, copper coils, two staff visiting C. U. for several months [tls]; reply, 3/18/1954 [cc], 3/4/1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Di Fisica, Pisa, to R.R.W., C. U., re distribution of lenses in synchrotron, separate proposal for machine with two different vertical directions [tls], diagram; reply, 4/20/1954 [cc], 4/6/1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Di Fisica, Pisa, from R.R.W., C. U., re progress of Pisa machine [cc], 6/17/1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Di Fisica, Pisa, to R.R.W., C. U., re visiting C. U. "in a period coinciding with your climbing to high energy," requests information and photograph of synchrotron for article G. S. is writing [tls]; reply, 8/9/1954 [cc], 6/16/1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, to R.R.W., C. U., re Glasgow Conference (telegram) [phc], 6/26/1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Instituto [sic] di Fisica, from R.R.W., re latest results in laboratory, beam at energy somewhat above 800 Mev, getting some 3x108 electrons per pulse, beam current of only 1 ma from Van der Graaff; plans to increase intensity, etc.; transfer of beam from F. M. cavity to F. F. cavity amazingly easy; redesigned pole tips help stability [cc], 8/2/1955 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Di Fisica, Pisa, to R.R.W., C. U., re news on progress of Pisa machine [tls], 12/23/1955 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Fisica, from G. Bernardini, re R.R.W.'s visit to Italy next summer, possibility of contacting R.R.W. in Moscow re schedule [cc], 4/30/1956 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Naszionale di Fisica Nucleare, Roma, to R.R.W., c/o Academy of Science, Moscow, re visit to Rome [tls], 5/14/1956 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Naszionale di Fisica Nucleare, Roma, to R.R.W., C. U., re substituting rubber strips for rubber pipes (diagram), [tls], note and drawing on recto [am], 9/8/1956 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Naszionale di Fisica Nucleare, Roma, to R.R.W., C. U., re hopes to visit LNS at time of Rochester Conference, building magnet "(according to our schedule)," redesigning coils with transposition of the Roebel type, donut of araldite and quartz [tls]; reply, 12/12/1956 [cc]; G. S. to R.R.W., 3/11/1957, re plans to visit [tls], 11/26/1956 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio: statement from R.R.W. regarding visit by G. S. to LNS and other U. S. laboratories, also declaring G. S. has received no money during his visits [cc], 4/24/1957 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Salvini, Giorgio, Istituto Naszionale di Fisica Nucleare, Roma, to R.R.W., C. U., re request for two more copies of book "The Cornell BeV Synchrotron," first two copies did not arrive, "starting the magnetic measurements on the first quadrant of our magnet" [tls], 10/21/1957 (Box 3, Folder 92)